const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A female patient came to the gynecology outpatient department (OPD) with a complaint of infertility. After lab investigation, it was found that the problem is with the conduction of sperms and ovum to the site of fertilization. What is the site of fertilization?","answers":[{"option":"Uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Fallopian tubes","bool":true},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false},{"option":"Vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following secretes Mullerian-inhibiting substance (MIS)?","answers":[{"option":"Granulosa cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":true},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular cells","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common contraceptive method used in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Diaphragm","bool":false},{"option":"Contraceptive ring","bool":false},{"option":"The oral contraceptive pill","bool":false},{"option":"Intrauterine device (IUD)","bool":false},{"option":"Condoms","bool":true}]},{"id":3,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following hormones is used to detect pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin (hCG)","bool":true},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Gubernaculum gives rise to which of the following structures in females?","answers":[{"option":"Labia minora","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine tubes","bool":false},{"option":"Uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Round ligament of the uterus","bool":true},{"option":"Glans clitoris","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Ovulation occurs in response to which of the following hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The proliferation of the corpus luteum is promoted by prolactin which stimulates the production of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Somatomedin","bool":false},{"option":"Thyrotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroxine","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is associated with increased estrogen levels in the body?","answers":[{"option":"Amenorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Klinefelter syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Gynecomastia","bool":true},{"option":"Sheehan syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hypofunctional ovaries","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which hormone influences the development of secondary sexual characteristics and menstruation in females?","answers":[{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Androgens","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"How many oocytes will a normal woman ovulate over her entire reproductive life?","answers":[{"option":"50","bool":false},{"option":"5400","bool":false},{"option":"40","bool":false},{"option":"450","bool":true},{"option":"540","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following increases in case of damage to the hypothalamus?","answers":[{"option":"Prolactin","bool":true},{"option":"Thyroid-stimulating hormone (TSH)","bool":false},{"option":"Anti-diuretic hormone (ADH)","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone (GH)","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Upon examination of endometrial tissue, spiral arteries are seen which are edematous.\r\nWhich phase is this seen in?","answers":[{"option":"Late secretory phase","bool":true},{"option":"Early secretory phase","bool":false},{"option":"Luteal phase","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular phase","bool":false},{"option":"Ovulation","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"During the menstrual cycle, progesterone will be highest in which phase?","answers":[{"option":"Late secretory phase","bool":false},{"option":"Ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"Luteal phase","bool":true},{"option":"Early secretory phase","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular phase","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of these cells are responsible for the production of testosterone?","answers":[{"option":"Hypothalamic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior pituitary cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":true},{"option":"Prostate gland cells","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The secretion of inhibin is caused by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":false},{"option":"Reticulocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Mast cells","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"At which stage during spermatogenesis do cells undergo first meiosis?","answers":[{"option":"Primordial germ cell","bool":false},{"option":"Spermatogonia","bool":false},{"option":"Primary spermatocyte","bool":true},{"option":"Spermatid","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary spermatocyte","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What hormones are primarily involved in lactation?","answers":[{"option":"Androgens","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Growth hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin and prolactin","bool":true}]},{"id":17,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the term anorchism defined as?","answers":[{"option":"Male born with both undescended testes","bool":false},{"option":"Male born without one testis","bool":false},{"option":"Male born with one undescended testis","bool":false},{"option":"Male born with both testes","bool":false},{"option":"Male born with no testes","bool":true}]},{"id":18,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Pelvic inflammatory disease (PID) is commonly caused by which bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Treponema pallidum","bool":false},{"option":"Yersinia pestis","bool":false},{"option":"Haemophilus ducreyi","bool":false},{"option":"Gardnerella vaginalis","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":true}]},{"id":19,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which is the main ligament of support for the uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Mesometrium","bool":false},{"option":"Broad ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Round ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Cardinal ligament","bool":true},{"option":"Arcuate ligament","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which is the most common site of implantation of the fetus in an ectopic pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Ampulla","bool":true},{"option":"Uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false},{"option":"Infundibulum","bool":false},{"option":"Isthmus","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Higher than normal levels of progesterone are found in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Anovulatory cycle","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital adrenal hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Ectopic pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Fetal death","bool":false},{"option":"Amenorrhea","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the major form of estrogen produced from menarche till menopause?","answers":[{"option":"Beta-estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"Esterol","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Estriol","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is/are the most active form/forms of estrogen?","answers":[{"option":"Estrone and estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Estriol","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is done to diagnose enlarged prostate with dysuria?","answers":[{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Computed tomography (CT scan)","bool":false},{"option":"Biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Urine culture","bool":true}]},{"id":25,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is involved in the conversion of androstenedione to testosterone?","answers":[{"option":"21-hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"17-hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"11β-hydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"17β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase","bool":true},{"option":"18-hydroxylase","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the most frequent cause of dysfunctional uterine bleeding?","answers":[{"option":"Endometritis","bool":false},{"option":"Leiomyoma","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic anovulation","bool":true},{"option":"Endometrial polyps","bool":false},{"option":"Diagnosis of exclusion with no known detectable cause","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is primarily a prolactin inhibiting factor?","answers":[{"option":"Metoclopramide","bool":false},{"option":"Haloperidol","bool":false},{"option":"Dopamine","bool":true},{"option":"Somatotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Vasopressin","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 47-year-old male presents to the clinic with an increased frequency of urination and dribbling urine. He often wakes up at night to urinate, 4-5 times at least and denies any history of back pain, burning micturition, and dysuria. His urinalysis shows no major changes. Based on these findings what is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Prostatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Benign prostatic hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"Sexually transmitted infection (STI)","bool":false},{"option":"Urethritis","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following will most likely be damaged by a stab wound into the\r\nischio-anal fossa 2 cm lateral to the anal canal?","answers":[{"option":"Vestibular bulb","bool":false},{"option":"Crus of penis","bool":false},{"option":"Perineal body","bool":false},{"option":"Pudendal nerve","bool":true},{"option":"Inferior rectal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Progesterone levels lower than normal may indicate which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital adrenal hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Menarche","bool":false},{"option":"Anovulatory cycles","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following usually causes acute bacterial prostatitis?","answers":[{"option":"Neisseria meningitidis","bool":false},{"option":"Chlamydia trachomatis","bool":false},{"option":"Stenotrophomonas maltophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following converts testosterone into estrogen?","answers":[{"option":"17β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"3β-hydroxysteroid dehydrogenase","bool":false},{"option":"Aromatase","bool":true},{"option":"5α-reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Enolase","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"When the internal iliac artery is damaged, what anastomosis provides compensation for blood flow?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral and middle colic artery","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral and interior rectal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Femoral and middle rectal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Superior and middle rectal artery","bool":true},{"option":"Femoral and superior rectal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What hormone causes the testes to descend into the scrotum?","answers":[{"option":"Testosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Androgen","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Cystic ovaries are observed on examination. What type of epithelium surrounds the follicles?","answers":[{"option":"Theca cells","bool":true},{"option":"Follicular cells","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerulosa cells","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cells","bool":false},{"option":"Basal cells","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Where are spermatozoa produced?","answers":[{"option":"Vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":true},{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Rete testis","bool":false},{"option":"Tunica albuginea","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which hormone causes the maturation of ovarian follicles?","answers":[{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Luteinizing hormone (LH)","bool":false},{"option":"Follicle-stimulating hormone (FSH)","bool":true},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin (HCG)","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which is not true about Sertoli cells?","answers":[{"option":"Are large and have irregular outlines","bool":false},{"option":"Have gap junctions","bool":true},{"option":"Are phagocytic","bool":false},{"option":"Are found in seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Nourish developing spermatids","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following aptly defines gender?","answers":[{"option":"How a patient identifies themselves","bool":false},{"option":"Difference in health problem","bool":false},{"option":"How a patient identifies themselves according to their roles in society","bool":true},{"option":"Biological differences","bool":false},{"option":"External appearance","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Major contribution to semen is from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":false},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Seminal vesicles","bool":true},{"option":"Epdidymis","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbourethral gland","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A student observes a slide with spherical concretions which appear to be made of concentric lamellae. The tissue observed is of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Seminal vesicle","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate gland","bool":true},{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbourethral gland","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"There is a gland between the posterior wall of the vagina and the labia minora. Which is it?","answers":[{"option":"Skene's glands","bool":false},{"option":"Bartholin's gland","bool":true},{"option":"Cowper's gland","bool":false},{"option":"Lesser vestibular gland","bool":false},{"option":"Ovaries","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which structure is most likely to get damaged during a hysterectomy?","answers":[{"option":"Ureter","bool":true},{"option":"Ovarian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ovarian ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Round ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine artery","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A student is checking the gender of a newborn but it is difficult to differentiate. The student must call upon his knowledge of the first determination of sex. When does this occur?","answers":[{"option":"Determination at fertilization","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Differentiation of indifferent gonad","bool":false},{"option":"Determined at puberty","bool":false},{"option":"Determined at oogenesis","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A patient presented with fever, chills, and suprapubic pain; on rectal examination, the prostate was tender. What is the next step in diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Urine culture","bool":true},{"option":"Computerized tomography (CT scan)","bool":false},{"option":"Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI)","bool":false},{"option":"Prostate massage and analysis of fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Ultrasound","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the effect of the luteinizing hormone (LH)?","answers":[{"option":"Helps control the production of sperm","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulates Leydig cells to make testosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Stimulates Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Prepares the endometrium for a potential pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulates the growth of eggs in the ovaries","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A patient presents with meatus showing on the dorsal side of the penis. What is this called?","answers":[{"option":"Cryptorchidism","bool":false},{"option":"Exstrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocele","bool":false},{"option":"Epispadias","bool":true},{"option":"Hypospadias","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A patient presents with meatus showing on the ventral side of the penis. What is this called?","answers":[{"option":"Hypospadias","bool":true},{"option":"Cryptorchidism","bool":false},{"option":"Epispadias","bool":false},{"option":"Exstrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocele","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The ductus deferens and the spermatic cord vessels come in contact with one another when\r\npassing through which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Scrotum","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Throughout their path","bool":false},{"option":"Inguinal canal","bool":true},{"option":"Abdomen","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Estrogen protects young women from myocardial infarction due to which of the following effects?","answers":[{"option":"Increase HDL","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease HDL and increase LDL","bool":false},{"option":"Increase HDL and decrease LDL","bool":true},{"option":"Decrease LDH","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease HDL and decrease LDL","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which is false regarding the placenta?","answers":[{"option":"Chorionic villi contain fetal vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Decidua basalis forms maternal part","bool":false},{"option":"Chorionic plate comes from fetus","bool":false},{"option":"The decidua capsularis is part of the maternal placenta","bool":true},{"option":"There is no mixing of blood","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which muscle may be damaged as a result of parturition?","answers":[{"option":"Depressor ani","bool":false},{"option":"Levator ani","bool":true},{"option":"Adductor longus","bool":false},{"option":"External sphincter muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Gracilis","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Where does the duct of an inflamed Bartholin's gland open?","answers":[{"option":"Between labia majora and vaginal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Vestibule","bool":true},{"option":"Outside the labia majora","bool":false},{"option":"Between labia minora and vaginal wall","bool":false},{"option":"Into Bartholin abscess","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which is not true about the stimulation of prostate?","answers":[{"option":"Stimulated by testosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Stimulated by dihydrotestosterone (DHT)","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulated under parasympathetic activity","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulated by rectal massage","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulated during sexual activity","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is a part of the urogenital diaphragm?","answers":[{"option":"Deep transverse perineal muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Perineal membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial transverse perineal muscle","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial perineal fascia","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is an intermediate in the biogenic synthesis of adrenocortical hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true}]},{"id":57,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is true about placental infection?","answers":[{"option":"It usually produces premature rupture of membranes","bool":true},{"option":"Does not cause chorioamnionitis","bool":false},{"option":"Does not cause funisitis","bool":false},{"option":"The spread is usually hematogenous","bool":false},{"option":"Does not cause villitis","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is the first hormone secreted by the placenta?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Testosterone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is involved in the development of ducts of breasts?","answers":[{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following lymph nodes do testes drain into?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Para-aortic lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Superficial inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Deep inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is involved in the lymphatic drainage of the glans penis?","answers":[{"option":"Femoral lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Iliac lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Deep inguinal lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"Popliteal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Lumbar lymph nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is the main hormone secreted by the placenta during pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The lower one-third of the vagina drains into which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial inguinal lymph nodes","bool":true},{"option":"The superficial inguinal and perirectal nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Deep inguinal lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac nodes","bool":false},{"option":"The common and internal iliac nodes","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding prostate?","answers":[{"option":"70% of prostate cancer originates in the peripheral zone","bool":false},{"option":"Central zone is around ejaculatory ducts","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional zone surrounds urethral meatus","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior lobe is mainly muscular","bool":true},{"option":"Anterior lobe is mainly fibrous","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following emergency contraceptive pills is prescribed to a couple who want to prevent pregnancy after unprotected sexual intercourse?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Tadalafil","bool":false},{"option":"Mifepristone","bool":false},{"option":"Norgestrel","bool":false},{"option":"Levonorgestrel","bool":true}]},{"id":66,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"During the 5th week, what is formed by the mesenchymal proliferation on the medial side of mesonephros?","answers":[{"option":"Genital ridge","bool":true},{"option":"Metanephric blastema","bool":false},{"option":"Testes","bool":false},{"option":"Efferent ductules","bool":false},{"option":"Kidneys","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is not one of the changes observed in a pregnant woman's circulatory system?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"No change in blood volume","bool":true},{"option":"Increased heart rate","bool":false},{"option":"Increased blood pressure","bool":false},{"option":"Increased cardiac output","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"When is the colostrum produced?","answers":[{"option":"A few days before and after parturition","bool":true},{"option":"Right after labor","bool":false},{"option":"One week after delivery","bool":false},{"option":"After conception","bool":false},{"option":"Two weeks after delivery","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which one of the following causes the opening on the ventral side of penis?","answers":[{"option":"Fusion of urethral folds is incomplete","bool":true},{"option":"Improper development of the pubic bone","bool":false},{"option":"Problematic development of cloacal membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Inadequate ectodermal-mesenchymal interactions during genital tubercle development","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 22-year-old medical student presents to the clinic with a history of weight gain, worsening and thickened facial hair, and irregular periods. What could she possibly be suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Cervical dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Pelvic pain","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome (PCOS)","bool":true},{"option":"Uterine fibroids","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Where along the course of the pudendal nerve is the anesthetic agent administered?","answers":[{"option":"Pubic symphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Sacrum","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial spine","bool":true},{"option":"Subpubic angle","bool":false},{"option":"Tip of coccyx","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"In which of the following, a complete absence of Mullerian ducts is seen?","answers":[{"option":"Mayer-Rokitansky-Küster-Hauser syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Ehlers-danlos syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Boerhaaves syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Gerstmann syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Zinner syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following do estrogen, progesterone and androgens act by?","answers":[{"option":"Ligand-activated ion channels and G protein-coupled receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Ligand-activated transcription factors","bool":true},{"option":"G protein-coupled receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Ligand-activated ion channels","bool":false},{"option":"Ligand-activated ion channels and ligand-activated transcription factors","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"In which of the following are androgen receptors found?","answers":[{"option":"Epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Cytoplasm","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Stroma","bool":false},{"option":"Endothelium","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following does the fertilization most commonly occur in?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian duct","bool":false},{"option":"Body","bool":false},{"option":"Fallopian tube","bool":true},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false},{"option":"Fundus","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is not required for fertilization?","answers":[{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Capacitation","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol from seminal vesicle","bool":true},{"option":"Acrosomal enzymes","bool":false},{"option":"Sperm and ovum","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"In pelvic inflammatory disease (PID), what does the gonococcal infection affect?","answers":[{"option":"Uterus","bool":false},{"option":"Cervix","bool":false},{"option":"Vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Vulva","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine tubes","bool":true}]},{"id":78,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Due to the protective effect of which of the following are women at a lower risk of cardiovascular diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Regarding male pelvis, which of the following is a correct statement?","answers":[{"option":"Shallow false pelvis","bool":false},{"option":"Inlet is either round or oval","bool":false},{"option":"Straighter and more flexible coccyx","bool":false},{"option":"Bones are lesser in weight and thickness","bool":false},{"option":"Subpubic angle is less than 90°","bool":true}]},{"id":80,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is the main function of testes?","answers":[{"option":"Production of oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Production of estrogen and eggs","bool":false},{"option":"Production of sperms and testosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Production of oxytocin","bool":false},{"option":"Production of progesterone","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is not a cause of cryptorchidism?","answers":[{"option":"Down syndrome or abnormal wall defect","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking by mother during pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH)","bool":true},{"option":"Alcohol consumption by mother during pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Premature birth","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is not true about the oviduct?","answers":[{"option":"Peg cells are ciliated","bool":true},{"option":"The muscle layer consists of an outer longitudinal layer and inner circular layer.","bool":false},{"option":"Intramural portion extends through the uterine wall","bool":false},{"option":"The proximal part is called isthmus","bool":false},{"option":"Intercalated cells are non-functional","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is not true about myometrium?","answers":[{"option":"It is also called compacta","bool":true},{"option":"It undergoes hyperplasia and hypertrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Arterial arcade lies in it","bool":false},{"option":"Its main function is to induce uterine contractions","bool":false},{"option":"It is sensitive to oxytocin","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following hormones can decrease the reception of sperms?","answers":[{"option":"Progesterone","bool":true},{"option":"Prolactin","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Androgens","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"In which of the following is endocrine therapy used as a palliative treatment?","answers":[{"option":"Ovarian carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine sarcoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cervical carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Metastatic breast cancer","bool":true}]},{"id":86,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following problems could be solved in postmenopausal women using exogenous estrogen?","answers":[{"option":"Menstrual cramps","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Lower back pain","bool":false},{"option":"Osteoporosis","bool":true},{"option":"Migraine","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following arteries is at the risk of most damage as a result of ovarian mass laparotomy?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Common iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Ovarian artery","bool":true}]},{"id":88,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following drains into the portal vein?","answers":[{"option":"External iliac vein","bool":false},{"option":"Middle rectal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac vein","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectal vein","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectal vein","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is more likely to get damaged during catheterization?","answers":[{"option":"Glans penis","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus cavernosum","bool":false},{"option":"Spongy urethra","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following ensures storage and maturation of sperms, and joins the ductus deferens?","answers":[{"option":"Seminiferous tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Epididymis","bool":true},{"option":"Efferent ductules","bool":false},{"option":"Penis","bool":false},{"option":"Rete testis","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is not true about Cowper's gland?","answers":[{"option":"They are tubuloalveolar","bool":false},{"option":"Their smooth muscles in septa form lobules","bool":false},{"option":"They are paired","bool":false},{"option":"Their ducts open into membranous urethra","bool":true},{"option":"Their epithelium is made of serous tall columnar cells","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following arteries is present behind the ovarian fossa?","answers":[{"option":"Common iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"External iliac artery","bool":false},{"option":"Internal iliac artery","bool":true},{"option":"Femoral artery","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior epigastric artery","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which one of the following is the precursor of progesterone?","answers":[{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Androgens","bool":false},{"option":"Estrone","bool":false},{"option":"Pregnenolone","bool":true},{"option":"Adrenal-derived C19 steroids","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of these increases reception of cervical mucus to the sperm movement?","answers":[{"option":"Mucus","bool":false},{"option":"Fructose","bool":false},{"option":"HCl","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatic fluid","bool":false},{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following best describes what finasteride is?","answers":[{"option":"A synthetic steroid to inhibit the action of progesterone to induce abortion","bool":false},{"option":"A drug used to lower blood sugar levels by improving the way human body handles insulin","bool":false},{"option":"An inhibitor of 5 alpha-reductase to prevent benign prostatic hyperplasia","bool":true},{"option":"A drug that competes with 17β-estradiol (E2) to block its promotional role in breast cancer","bool":false},{"option":"An anti-cancer chemotherapy drug","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following set defines the factors that affect 'empowerment'?","answers":[{"option":"People and resources","bool":false},{"option":"Resources","bool":false},{"option":"People, resources, and events","bool":true},{"option":"Natural disasters","bool":false},{"option":"People like elected officials","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Ideally, when should intrauterine devices (IUDs) be implanted?","answers":[{"option":"During menstruation","bool":true},{"option":"After menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"Before menstruation","bool":false},{"option":"Before ovulation","bool":false},{"option":"Mid cycle","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is odd regarding Graffian follicle?","answers":[{"option":"Cumulus oophorus","bool":false},{"option":"Zona pellucida","bool":false},{"option":"Primary oocyte","bool":true},{"option":"Liquor folliculi","bool":false},{"option":"Theca folliculi","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following are the most common problems related to sexual dysfunction in males?","answers":[{"option":"Erectile dysfunction","bool":false},{"option":"Early ejaculation and loss of sexual interest","bool":false},{"option":"Erectile dysfunction and loss of sexual interest","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Erectile dysfunction, early ejaculation and loss of sexual interest","bool":true}]},{"id":100,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"In which of the following areas, the expelled contents of the rectum will not be collected in case it gets ruptured?","answers":[{"option":"Rectouterine pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Rectovesical pouch","bool":false},{"option":"Pararectal fossae","bool":false},{"option":"Retrorectal space","bool":false},{"option":"Uterovesical pouch","bool":true}]},{"id":101,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"As a result of damage to the spongy urethra, where does the urine start to escape into?","answers":[{"option":"Superficial perineal pouch","bool":true},{"option":"Rectum","bool":false},{"option":"Ureter","bool":false},{"option":"Corpus cavernosum","bool":false},{"option":"Bladder","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following structures is present only in a male?","answers":[{"option":"Sphincter urethrae","bool":false},{"option":"Genital hiatus","bool":false},{"option":"Ischiocavernous sinus","bool":false},{"option":"Recto-vesical pouch","bool":true},{"option":"Ischiopubic ramus","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"If a woman has her right uterine tube blocked at the isthmus and the left uterine tube is resected, what will be the result?","answers":[{"option":"Fertilization can occur but no implantation","bool":false},{"option":"Fertlization but implantation at ectopic site","bool":false},{"option":"No fertilization and no implantation","bool":true},{"option":"Fertilization and implanation in uterus","bool":false},{"option":"No fertilization","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of these is an estrogen oral contraceptive?","answers":[{"option":"Norgesterol","bool":false},{"option":"Estradiol","bool":false},{"option":"Androstenedione","bool":false},{"option":"Mestranol","bool":true},{"option":"Cimetidrol","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following features is the most prominent and can be used to identify fallopian tubes?","answers":[{"option":"Simple squamous epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified columnar epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Highly branched mucosal longitudinal folds","bool":true},{"option":"Muscularis has three layers; longitudinal, circular, and oblique","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified columnar epithelium","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A deficiency of iodine in maternal blood can cause which condition in a child?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperthyroidism","bool":false},{"option":"Calcium deficiency","bool":false},{"option":"Diabetes mellitus","bool":false},{"option":"Goiter","bool":false},{"option":"Hypothyroidism","bool":true}]},{"id":107,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"In which stage of pregnancy, are women most prone to get anemia?","answers":[{"option":"1st trimester","bool":false},{"option":"2nd month","bool":false},{"option":"7th month","bool":true},{"option":"1st month","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the most common symptom of endometrial hyperplasia?","answers":[{"option":"Vaginal discharge","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary incontinence","bool":false},{"option":"Vaginal bleeding","bool":true},{"option":"Vaginal pain","bool":false},{"option":"Pubic pain","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The ducts of seminal glands and ductus deferens fuse to form which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Vas deferens","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Spongy urethra","bool":false},{"option":"Epididymis","bool":false},{"option":"Ejaculatory duct","bool":true}]},{"id":110,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which muscle forms the major portion of the pelvic diaphragm along with its fellow muscle?","answers":[{"option":"Pubococcygeus","bool":false},{"option":"Puborectalis","bool":false},{"option":"Levator ani","bool":true},{"option":"Coccygeus","bool":false},{"option":"Iliococcygeus","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"The fascia of the pelvic diaphragm does not attach to which of the following structures of pelvis?","answers":[{"option":"Pubic ramus","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ischial spine","bool":false},{"option":"Pubic body","bool":false},{"option":"Iliac crest","bool":true}]},{"id":112,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Regarding the blood-testis barrier, which of the following is the most inappropriate statement?","answers":[{"option":"Formed by contact of lateral processes of Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Only present in basal compartment of seminiferous tubules","bool":true},{"option":"Formed by Sertoli cells","bool":false},{"option":"Prevents autoimmune reaction of secondary spermatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Is present in adluminal compartment","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following structures produces inhibin?","answers":[{"option":"Sertoli cells","bool":true},{"option":"Parietal cells","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Leydig cells","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is the suitable differential diagnosis for per vaginal blood?","answers":[{"option":"Perforation of bladder and vagina","bool":true},{"option":"Rectouterine opening","bool":false},{"option":"An opening between bladder and vagina","bool":false},{"option":"Vesicovaginal fistula that occurs after delivery","bool":false},{"option":"Vesicovaginal opening","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following nervous contents is not present in the ischioanal fossae?","answers":[{"option":"Branches of S2, S3","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior rectal","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior scrotal/ labial","bool":false},{"option":"Superior rectal","bool":true},{"option":"Perineal branches of S4","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A 19-year-old female, whose first menstrual period started 5 years ago is visiting her physician for several years. Last year she was diagnosed with oligomenorrhea and in the past month, she got hirsutism and has gained ten kilograms of weight. On ultrasound, there are no significant abdominal findings but the pelvis shows twice the size of the ovaries. What is her diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cyst adenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Tubo-ovarian abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic ovarian syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Kurkenburg tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrial polyps","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of these is a feature of the male pelvis that is not present in the female pelvis?","answers":[{"option":"Larger pelvic inlet","bool":false},{"option":"Round pelvic inlet","bool":false},{"option":"Straight sacral curvature","bool":false},{"option":"Larger pelvic outlet","bool":false},{"option":"Smaller pubic angle","bool":true}]},{"id":118,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Prostate cancer occurs in which zone of the prostate?","answers":[{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false},{"option":"Transitional","bool":false},{"option":"Peripheral","bool":true},{"option":"Central","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is the most common cause of the puerperal pelvic inflammatory disease (PID)?","answers":[{"option":"Bacterial vaginosis","bool":false},{"option":"E. coli ascending through urinary tract","bool":false},{"option":"Neisseria gonorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Polybacterial","bool":true},{"option":"Chlamydia","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A primigravida has a 12-week gestation, has complaints of amenorrhea, presented for her antenatal checkup. The doctor is unable to detect a fetal heartbeat. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Intrauterine growth restriction","bool":false},{"option":"Threatened abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Spontaneous abortion","bool":false},{"option":"Molar pregnancy","bool":false},{"option":"Missed abortion","bool":true}]},{"id":121,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Ovarian stroma is chiefly composed of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Nerves","bool":false},{"option":"Spindle shaped cells","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphatic vessels","bool":false},{"option":"Vascular sinusoids","bool":false},{"option":"Ground substance","bool":false}]},{"id":122,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of these is true regarding the uterus?","answers":[{"option":"Has no sympathetic supply","bool":false},{"option":"Majorly supported by broad ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Covered more by peritoneum posteriorly than anteriorly","bool":true},{"option":"Made up of fibrous layer only","bool":false},{"option":"Derives its entire blood supply from uterine artery with no collateral supply","bool":false}]},{"id":123,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is present in the superficial perineal pouch?","answers":[{"option":"Bulbospongiosus","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal nerve of penis","bool":false},{"option":"Sphincter urethrae","bool":false},{"option":"Bulbourethral glands","bool":false},{"option":"Entire spongy urethra","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the meaning of empowerment?","answers":[{"option":"Control over community","bool":false},{"option":"Control over others","bool":false},{"option":"Control over environment","bool":false},{"option":"Control over one's own life","bool":true},{"option":"Control over society","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A doctor after a thorough examination diagnosed a patient with benign prostatic hyperplasia. He gives him 5-alpha reductase inhibitor to decrease which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Testosterone conversion to dihydrotestosterone","bool":true},{"option":"Testosterone conversion to angiotensin II","bool":false},{"option":"Testosterone conversion to 5-alpha reductase","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensinogen conversion to angiotensin","bool":false},{"option":"Angiotensin conversion to angiotensin II","bool":false}]},{"id":126,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which branch of the iliac artery is most likely to get resected during hysterectomy?","answers":[{"option":"Inferior rectal artery","bool":false},{"option":"Uterine artery","bool":true},{"option":"Ovarian artery","bool":false},{"option":"Obturator artery","bool":false},{"option":"Middle rectal artery","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"High levels of serum progesterone during pregnancy are secreted by which structure?","answers":[{"option":"Oviduct","bool":false},{"option":"Placenta","bool":true},{"option":"Corpus luteum","bool":false},{"option":"Endometrium","bool":false},{"option":"Ovary","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"A sudden decrease in the circulatory levels of which placental hormone indicates a nonviable pregnancy?","answers":[{"option":"Luteinizing hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Estrogen","bool":false},{"option":"Progesterone","bool":false},{"option":"Human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":true},{"option":"Follicle stimulating hormone","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Progesterone increases in which phase of the female reproductive cycle?","answers":[{"option":"Menstrual phase","bool":false},{"option":"Decline phase","bool":false},{"option":"Oligomenorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Follicular phase","bool":false},{"option":"Luteal phase","bool":true}]},{"id":130,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"What is the therapeutic use for estrogen replacement therapy?","answers":[{"option":"Most effective when given right after menopause","bool":false},{"option":"Restores bone loss due to osteoporosis","bool":true},{"option":"Used to treat oligomenorrhea","bool":false},{"option":"Used to treat hirsutism","bool":false},{"option":"Requires higher doses than given for contraception","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which is not a complication of pelvic inflammatory disease?","answers":[{"option":"Intestinal obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Tubovarian abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Bacteremia","bool":false},{"option":"Endometriosis","bool":true},{"option":"Infertility","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Sacrum does not attach to which of these structures?","answers":[{"option":"Left ilium","bool":false},{"option":"Fifth lumbar vertebra","bool":false},{"option":"Right ilium","bool":false},{"option":"Coccyx","bool":false},{"option":"Ischium","bool":true}]},{"id":133,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Sacral cornua are formed by which of these?","answers":[{"option":"Transverse process of sacral vertebrae","bool":false},{"option":"Foramen at anterior surface","bool":false},{"option":"Inferior articular process of S5","bool":true},{"option":"Superior articular process","bool":false},{"option":"Spinous process of S3","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of these is a fact about the ovary?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Germinal epithelium is not a source of germ cells","bool":true},{"option":"Ovary is a purely exocrine gland","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cells are formed from stroma","bool":false},{"option":"Germinal epithelium is under the tunica albuginea","bool":false}]},{"id":135,"info":"2nd-year/reproductive/2019","question":"Which of the following is the rate-limiting enzyme in cholesterol synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Mevalonate carboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA reductase","bool":true},{"option":"Prenyl transferase","bool":false},{"option":"HMG-CoA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Squalene synthase","bool":false}]}]
export default arr